The truth lies beyond the wall.
Allegiant is a adventure, science fiction, action
film directed by Robert Schwentke.
Beatrice Prior and Tobias Eaton venture into the world outside of the fence and are taken into
protective custody by a mysterious agency known as the Bureau of Genetic Welfare.
Beatrice 'Tris' Prior, played by Shailene Woodley.
Tobias 'Four' Eaton, played by Theo James.
Peter Hayes, played by Miles Teller.
Christina, played by Zoë Kravitz.
Evelyn Johnson-Eaton, played by Naomi Watts.
David, played by Jeff Daniels.
The Divergent Series: Allegiant (simply known as Allegiant) is a 2016 American dystopian science fiction action film directed by Robert
Schwentke with a screenplay by Bill Collage, Adam Cooper, and Noah Oppenheim, and the third and final film in The Divergent Series.
It was set to be the first of two cinematic parts based on the 2013 novel Allegiant of the
Divergent trilogy by Veronica Roth (the second cinematic part was to be named Ascendant).
The film stars Shailene Woodley, Theo James, Jeff Daniels, Miles Teller, Ansel Elgort, Zoë
Kravitz, Maggie Q, Ray Stevenson, Bill Skarsgård, Octavia Spencer, and Naomi Watts.
Set in a post-apocalyptic and dystopian Chicago, the story follows Tris Prior, her boyfriend Four,
and their small group of friends escaping over the wall that enclosed the city.
Once outside they discover new truths that will shift
their alliances and introduce new threats.
Principal photography primarily took place in Atlanta,
Georgia, from May 2015 until August that same year.
The film was initially titled The Divergent Series: Allegiant – Part 1, in
September 2015, Part 1 was renamed Allegiant and Part 2 as Ascendant.
Allegiant was released on March 18, 2016 by Lionsgate under the
Summit Entertainment label, in theaters and IMAX.
It received generally negative reviews from critics, who criticized the lack of originality,
character development, and the decision to split the film into two parts.
The film was a box-office disappointment, grossing just $179.2 million worldwide against its estimated
budget of $110–142 million, making in the lowest-grossing film in The Divergent Series.
Following budget cuts, a theatrical release for Ascendant was dropped in favor of reconfiguring the
project as a television film for Starz that would be followed by a spinoff series.
Both projects were later canceled, effectively ending the franchise.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
revolution, dystopia, sequel, transhumanism.
The tone is thought_provoking and mind_bending.